# Varun Soni

# UI UX Designer and Frontend Developer

☑ ivarun.soni1502@gmail.com

+44 7823891934

https://www.behance.net/ivarunsoni

I am a professional UI UX Designer with over 6 years of industry experience and strong understanding of Colour Theory, Design Principles, Design Systems(Google's Material Design, HIG and Shopify Polaris), I am committed to providing human-centric and equitable designs. I stay upto-date with the latest design and technology trends, and thrive in fast-paced, collaborative environments.

My passion for UI/UX Design is reflected in my portfolio of successful projects which includes: **Qloapps** - Booking and Reservation System, **Shopify Multivendor Marketplace**, **Shopify Apps**, **UVDesk** - Helpdesk and Ticket System and over 200 Apps and Stand Alone Applications.

## **Experience**



#### **UI UX Designer**

Freelancer on fiverr.com

Dec 2021 - May 2023 · 1 yr 6 mo

Currently I am working as a Freelancer on Fiverr.com



### **UI UX Designer**

Webkul Software Pvt Ltd · Full-time

Dec 2014 - Sep 2021 · 6 yr 9 mo

- Creating intuitive and user-friendly interfaces for web and mobile applications.
- Creating Wireframes, Low and Hi-Fidelity Prototypes.
- Developing responsive designs that adapt to different screen sizes and devices and code as well.
- Utilizing modern frontend technologies such as HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Designing for Open source eCommerce Platforms like: Shopify, Magento, Wordpress Woocommerce, Prestashop and Odoo(CRM)
- Designing visual elements: Creating high-quality visual elements such as icons, logos, illustrations, and infographics.



# **Graphics Designer**

Just About Infratech Pvt Ltd · Full-time

Aug 2013 - Sep 2014 · 1 yr 1 mo

- Designing graphics: Using design software like Adobe InDesign, Illustrator, and Photoshop to create high-quality graphics and visual elements such as logos, illustrations, and infographics.
- Developing layouts: Creating visually pleasing layouts for print media, including magazines, brochures, books, and packaging.

#### **Education**



# **Google UX Design Certificate**

# Certification from Google

- Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design
- Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, and Ideate
- Build Wireframes and LowFidelity Prototypes
- Conduct UX Research and Test Early Concepts
- Create High-Fidelity Designs and Prototypes in Figma
- Responsive Web Design in Adobe XD
- Design a User Experience for Social Good & Prepare for Jobs

Post Graduation



# MSc. Marketing

Degree from Ulster University, Birmingham, UK

Sep 2021 - Apr 2023



#### **Under Graduation**

Bachelor's degree, Art/Art Studies, General

Delhi University, New Delhi, India

Apr 2011 - Feb 2015



# Web, Graphic Design and Animation Diploma

MAAC - Maya Academy of Advance Cinematic, New Delhi, India

Feb 2012 - Jul 2013

# **My Tools**

- · Sketch App
- Figma
- · Adobe XD CC
- · Invision Studio
- Miro
- Framer
- Notion
- Github(VCS)
- Adobe Creative Suite
- · Visual Studio Code

# My Profile Links

Dribbble: <a href="https://dribbble.com/ivarunsoni">https://dribbble.com/ivarunsoni</a>

Behance: <a href="https://www.behance.net/ivarunsoni">https://www.behance.net/ivarunsoni</a>

Codepen: <a href="https://codepen.io/ivarun">https://codepen.io/ivarun</a>

Medium: <a href="https://medium.com/@ivarunsoni">https://medium.com/@ivarunsoni</a>

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/varun-soni-39293a139/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/varun-soni-39293a139/</a>

# **Work Expamples**

Shopify Apps: <a href="https://apps.shopify.com/partners/webkul">https://apps.shopify.com/partners/webkul</a>

Qloapps: <a href="https://qloapps.com/">https://qloapps.com/</a>

Shopify MVM: <a href="https://apps.shopify.com/multi-vendor-marketplace?">https://apps.shopify.com/multi-vendor-marketplace?</a>

surface\_intra\_position=1&surface\_type=partners&surfac

<u>e\_version=redesign</u>